<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What? Like it's hard? (Posts about dactyl)</title><link>https://jennetters.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://jennetters.github.io/categories/dactyl.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:jennette.reid@gmail.com"&gt;J.Net&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 03:25:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>3D Printing a Dactyl... Attempt 1 of ??</title><link>https://jennetters.github.io/posts/2018-09-07-3d-printing-trials/</link><dc:creator>J.Net</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making a keyboard off of a purchased PCB has been fun, but like any good mechanical keyboard junkie, you very quickly discover that it's a slippery slope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole reason I started on this journey was to be able to get my hands on the most ergonomic keyboard, for my poor hands, that I could possibly find. And it wasn't long before I started lusting after a Dactyl of my very own. With no readily available PCB's it's a bit more of a challenge to build, but I think after building 2 keyboards successfully, I can figure it out with a little help from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that brings me to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step one - Picking the right Dactyl for my needs.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the easy part. I really like the Dactyl Manuform and think the 5x6 is ideal: https://github.com/tshort/dactyl-keyboard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been flip-flopping between the Iris (50%) and Fourier (40%) and like them both quite a bit, for different reasons, but I think that the Iris is a bit more user-friendly for everyday use. That's the main reason why, I'm opting for more keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step two - Building the case. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D Printing is finicky business. I purchased a second-hand printer to learn the ropes and with hopes of getting a Dactyl out of it. It was clear from the start that the resolution was more suited to drafts but I still had high hopes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of tinkering and practicing on smaller items to iron out the details, I was ready to give the Dactyl a go... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="imgur-embed-pub" lang="en" data-id="GMI8ns0"&gt;&lt;a href="//imgur.com/GMI8ns0"&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src="//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it was clearly a failure. &lt;em&gt;sigh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>3d printing</category><category>dactyl</category><category>mechanical keyboard</category><category>ortholinear</category><category>split mechanical keyboard</category><guid>https://jennetters.github.io/posts/2018-09-07-3d-printing-trials/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 19:01:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>